Simon Goldin

Simon.Goldin@gmail.com

Experienced Software Engineer - NYC / Philadelphia / Remote

Experienced full stack engineer with a focus on the front-end using modern tools and best practices across different industries. Experienced in different processes as well as management and mentoring, with a history of working with non-engineers to bring polished applications and features to B2B and B2C customers. Always refactoring and improving

Work Experience

Owner & Lead Developer @ Digital Canvas Development

June 2023 to Present; Remote/NJ

Returned to freelancing and consulting by launching Digital Canvas LLC and providing web development services to local businesses and tech startups.

Consulting, developing, and updating web properties (pre-existing or not). Preferred stack (currently): Remix, TypeScript, AWS or fly.io, Jest, Cypress, Prima ORM.

Managing Squarespace, WordPress, Shopify, etc. properties, website hosting and domain registration.

Staff Frontend Engineer @ Dashlane

August 2022 to June 2023; Remote

Core front-end development of web applications and extensions in the internet security field relying on a zero-knowledge architecture.

Frontend tech lead for numerous B2B-focused products and features specifically around secure SCIM and SSO integrations using Confidential Computing technologies.

Defining and iterating frontend architectures within a larger zero-knowledge architecture and context; some of this work involves cryptography, while other aspects involve user experience and design. Gathering requirements from product, design, and sales teams to improve existing and in-progress features.

Defining and circulating best practices across the frontend engineering team; regular code reviewing, mentoring, and holding remote ensemble- and pair-programming sessions with others as well as participating in and leading cross-functional efforts.

Engineering Manager @ Dashlane

November 2021 to April 2022; Remote

I managed 5 frontend engineers developing the B2B product across two teams, but ultimately decided to return to the technical leadership track.

Interviewed and hired engineers across two US-based teams. Held regular 1:1s with my reports and guided them in their careers and assisted with technical challenges.

Senior Frontend Engineer @ Dashlane

October 2019 to August 2022; New York, NY & Remote

Led development of underlying tools and dependencies including a custom component library (CSS-in-JS, React, TypeScript) and supporting documentation.

Responsible for making application-wide improvements to code quality, long-term maintenance, and developer experience.

Led development on B2B products including zero-knowledge SSO/SCIM authentication.

Senior Full Stack Engineer @ TripleLift

January 2018 to October 2019; New York, NY

In addition to responsibilities below: mentorship of other engineers; wrote and discussed technical specifications across the team, improved workflow, processes, and developer experience. Led a cross-team project to build a customized, reusable, and scalable component library leveraging Material UI (React, TypeScript).

Full Stack Engineer @ TripleLift

August 2015 to January 2018; New York, NY

Developed and maintained a variety of applications in AngularJS, React (and TypeScript), PHP, Go, and NodeJS for internal and external users for campaign and creative management, as well as JS code used on publishers' sites.

Heavily involved in application architecture decisions as well as hiring, code reviews, providing business context to engineers, and technology context to non-engineering teams.

Software Engineer @ play2prep

August 2013 to July 2015; New York, NY

Worked with management and designers to develop a test preparation studying mobile app for iOS and Android phones and tablets using Cordova, Grunt, Bower, NPM, AngularJS, SCSS, Java, and Apache Thrift.

Programmer @ TMCBonds LLC.

October 2010 to August 2013; New York, NY

Implemented solutions to improve developer and user experience and features with JavaScript and ExtJS; Supported monthly releases; Monitored stability of website supporting \$150M in daily trades. Led development of mobile application using Sencha Touch and pre-existing Java backend.

Web Developer @ Rutgers University

January 2009 to October 2010; NJ

Helped develop the official Rutgers School of Engineering website and other Drupal-based sites for Rutgers University. Took on system administration roles in a LAMP (PHP) server environment.

Freelance Web Developer

April 2007 to August 2015

Developed websites using WordPress, Drupal, vanillaJS and jQuery, as necessary for a particular project. Followed strict deadlines to complete projects to client specifications for small businesses and organizations. Often worked concurrently on multiple websites to create production code from sketches and mockups (PDFs, PSDs, pen & paper, etc)

Education

Rutgers University School of Engineering

New Brunswick, New Jersey

Bachelor of Science in Computer and Electrical Engineering, May 2010. Electrical Engineering; Digital Signal Processing, Sensors & Networking Systems.

Technical Expertise

Languages & Frameworks

React, NodeJS; unit testing with Jest, React Testing Library, others; NextJS, Remix, Gatsby; Emotion, styled-components, CSS-in-JS, TailwindCSS, LESS & SCSS; HTML5 & CSS3; TypeScript, JavaScript, NPM/Yarn/PNPM, PHP, Java, Go, MySQL, MongoDB.

Software & Tools

Mac OS X, Windows, Linux; debugging tools (Chrome & FireFox DevTools, xdebug); git, gitlab, github; JetBrains Intellij IDEA & WebStorm, vim; Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator; comfortable with sysadmin tasks and command line tools; AWS; Single-Page Applications (SPA), Multi-Page Applications (MPA), Server-Side Rendering (SSR), Browser Extensions.